A Guide to the Condominiums: Applications for Registration, 1979-1984
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Condominiums: Applications for Registration, 1979-1984
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 116
11 boxes.
Virginia Real Estate Commission
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Transfered from the Arlington Department of Community Affairs in the mid 1980s.
Scope and Content
RG 116 consists of condominium conversion information for Arlington properties and applications for registration. The material includes accompanying documents such as by-laws, revised applications, supplements to applications, public offering statements, and unit purchasing agreements. These applications were submitted to the Virginia Real Estate Commission. This collection dates 1979-1984 and is 3.6 linear feet. There are also two files of brochures advertising the new condominiums.
Arrangement
Series 1 contains information on the contents of the collection and its donation to the Center for Local History. The majority of the collection is in Series 2 and is arranged in alphabetical order by condominium. Series 3 contains condominium brochures, which are filed in alphabetical order by property name.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
For more information about the early days of apartment conversion to condominiums in Arlington, see RG 34, Records of Tenants of Arlington County. RG 325, Brian H. Ford Colonial Village Collection and RG 372, Nnoka Colonial Village Materials have more information on Colonial Village specifically.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Condominiums.; Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- Record Keeping
  - Memorandum regarding this material being donated to the library (Box 1)
- Applications
  - Adams House Condominium, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Arbors of Arlington, A Condominium, 1982 (1) (Box 1)
  - Arbors of Arlington, A Condominium, 1982 (2) (Box 1)
  - Arlington House Condominium, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Balmoral Condominium (formerly Lee House Apartments), 1984 (1) (Box 1)
  - Balmoral Condominium (formerly Lee House Apartments), 1984 (2) (Box 2)
  - Cardinal House Condominium, 1982 (includes architecural plans) (1) (Box 2)
  - Cardinal House Condominium, 1982 (includes architectural plans) (2) (Box 2)
  - The Carlton, A Condominium, 1983 (1) (Box 2)
  - The Carlton, A Condominium, 1983 (2) (Box 2)
  - Carlyn Place, A Condominium, 1984 (1) (Box 3)
  - Carlyn Place, A Condominium, 1984 (2) (Box 3)
  - Cambridge Courts Condominium, 1984 (1) (Box 3)
  - Cambridge Courts Condominium, 1984 (2) (Box 3)
  - The Chatham, A Condominium (a three-ring binder), 1979 (Box 3)
  - The Cavendish, A Condominium, 1980 (1) (Box 4)
  - The Cavendish, A Condominium, 1980 (2) (Box 4)
  - The Clarendon House, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Colonial Village (Village I), A Condominium, 1981 (1) (Box 4)
  - Colonial Village (Village I), A Condominium, 1981 (2) (Box 4)
  - Colonial Village (Village II), A Condominium, 1984 (3) (Box 5)
  - Colonial Village (Village II), A Condominium, 1984 (4) (Box 5)
  - Colonial Village (Village II), A Condominium, 1984 (5) (Box 5)
  - Georgetown Vista Condominium, 1983 (1) (Box 5)
  - Georgetown Vista Condominium, 1983 (2) (Box 5)
  - Harvey Hall Condominium (architectural plans and plat map), 1985 (Box 5)
  - The Lancaster, A Condominium, 1982 (1) (Box 6)
  - The Lancaster, A Condominium, 1982 (2) (Box 6)
  - The Palisades, A Condominium, 1982 (Box 6)
  - The Palisades Garden, A Condominium, 1983 (1) (Box 6)
  - The Palisades Garden, A Condominium, 1983 (2) (Box 6)
  - Quinn Court, A Condominium, 1982 (Box 7)
  - River Place (formerly Arlington Towers), 1981 (1) (Box 7)
  - River Place (formerly Arlington Towers), 1981 (2) (Box 7)
  - Stratton House Condominium, 1983 (1) (Box 7)
  - Stratton House Condominium, 1983 (2) (Box 7)
  - Stoneridge Knoll, A Condominium, 1986 (1) (Box 8)
  - Stoneridge Knoll, A Condominium, 1986 (2) (Box 8)
  - Stoneridge Knoll, A Condominium, 1986 (3) (Box 8)
  - Stoneridge Knoll, A Condominium, 1986 (4) (Box 8)
  - Stoneridge Knoll, A Condominium, 1986 (5) (Box 8)
  - Stoneridge Knoll, A Condominium, 1986 (6) (Box 8)
  - Taft Towers, A Condominium, 1980 (Box 9)
  - Tanglewood Condominium, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Walter Reed Gardens Condominium, 1982 (1) (Box 9)
  - Walter Reed Gardens Condominium, 1982 (2) (Box 9)
  - Walter Reed Gardens Condominium, 1982 (3) (Box 9)
  - Walter Reed Gardens Condominium, 1983 (4) (Box 10)
  - The Wentworth, A Condominium, 1984 (1) (Box 10)
  - The Wentworth, A Condominium, 1984 (2) (Box 10)
  - The Wentworth, A Condominium, 1984 (3) (Box 10)
  - The Westmoreland Terrace Condominium, 1981 (1) (Box 10)
  - The Westmoreland Terrace Condominium, 1981 (2) (Box 10)
  - Westmoreland Terrace Condominium, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Block Grant Reports, 1982, 1984 (Box 11)
- Brochures
  - Brochures A-H (Box 11)
  - Brochures P-W (Box 11)